Camille Sanchez

06-47-95-11-23 • camille.sanchez94@gmail.com • www.linkedin.com/in/camille-sanchez-media/ • Paris, France

Associate Producer & Communications Analyst

I am a bilingual (French-English) Video & Multimedia Producer and Communications Officer specializing in research, writing, production and directing videos. I excel at producing brand marketing content and crafting CSR messaging designed for audience impact. I also coordinated major campaigns by working with internal and external partners, fulfilling administrative responsibilities and ensuring timely completion of the project within budget. I am also very skilled at programming with Python, frontend languages and a few database languages.

SKILLS

- Research, Content
 Development, Copywriting & Editing
- Graphic & Visual Displays
- Directing, Producing & Scriptwriting & Editing
- Lighting, Audio & Camera
- Animation

- Website Optimization
- Project Management
- Multimedia Supervision & Coordination with Agences

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Multimedia Analyst - Marketing & Communications | BNP PARIBAS CIB AMERICAS | Sept. 2018 - Present | New York, USA

- Created a small production studio to handle multimedia requests and their progress, including trackable metrics, a multimedia procedure and a project database of approved multimedias
- Oversaw and produced original content to inform the staff of the bank's initiatives and engagement campaigns, to provide essential updates on behalf of departments and executives, and to highlight the bank's presence and sponsored events in the Americas

Postgraduate Intern, Multimedia Analyst - Marketing & Communications | BNP PARIBAS CIB AMERICAS |Sept. 2017 - Aug. 2018 | New York, USA

Hired as a "Volontariat International en Entreprise" (V.I.E), and transitioned to a full-time employee.

- Took over most photo and video projects assigned to agencies and supervised the remaining ones
- Laid the foundations for a studio and developed new content (videos, photos, infographics, etc.)

Lab & Production Assistant – CAMS Production Office | CARLETON COLLEGE | Sept. 2014 – Jun. 2017 | Northfield, USA

Assisted students and professors in building their projects and teaching materials (advised on equipment use, ensured equipment's safety, supported & managed the production of projects)

INTERNSHIP EXPERIENCE

Production Assistant | FINE ART CUBE PRODUCTION COMPANY | Summer 2016 | Paris Greater Area, FR Assisted artist Gerard Rancinan in producing photography project *Abuse of Power*

Digital Account Planning Assistant | PUBLICIS CONSEIL | Summer 2015 | Paris Greater Area, FR
Conducted industry research to improve brand positioning of prominent client & designed weekly internal newsletters for another important client

Web Assistant for TMC and NT1 | TF1 TELEVISION CHANNEL | Summer 2014 | Paris Greater Area, FR Researched competitors' websites to optimize exposure & produced photo reportage for French TV series

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in **Cinema and Media Studies** (CAMS) | Carleton College| Graduated in 2017 | Northfield, USA Introduction to **Programming with Python** diploma | New York University SPS| Graduated in 2020 | New York, USA

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE:

» Graphic Design, Photography, Video & Animation Software: Adobe Creative Cloud, Final Cut Pro, Dragonframe, Toon Boom Harmony and Studio Anime Pro

» Equipment Expertise:

- Camera: SONY HXR-NXSU, DSLR Canon 60D & Lumix GH5
- Audio: Shotgun Equipment, Lavelier microphones and audio recorders
- Lighting: Halogen and LED

» Programming Languages: Python, HTML, CSS, SQL and notions of Javascript

LANGUAGES:

French: NativeEnglish: Bilingual

» **Spanish:** Intermediate

HOBBIES:

- Sports: Competitive swimming (member of the Carleton College Division III Varsity team), sailing, alpine skiing
- » Entertainment: Cinema (films, documentaries, animations and TV Series) and Musicals